<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>BCIT CST</title>
    <link>http://www.bcitcst.com/categories/term-1/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on BCIT CST</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://www.bcitcst.com/categories/term-1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>BUSA 2720 - Business in a Networked Economy</title>
      <link>http://www.bcitcst.com/post/term1/busa2720/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2016 22:44:36 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.bcitcst.com/post/term1/busa2720/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This course can be pretty challenging if you don&amp;rsquo;t have the right resources. The instructor tries to make sure that everyone passes (because he hates doing the paperwork when someone fails), but the challenge is to do well in this course. Majority of the marks come from quizzes, and exams. This course is completely based on the textbook that he uses, and he&amp;rsquo;ll show you a lot of videos in lectures (half the lectures consist of these. Most the assignments are based on the videos so you can either watch them or get your friend who went to summarize it for you ;). Your primary focus should be the textbook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His lectures are super boring, really hard to stay focused but the good news is you don&amp;rsquo;t have to! You don&amp;rsquo;t even need to show up to them. The labs, however, are pretty useful and he summarizes all the useful stuff. His powerpoint notes are quite useful, they summarize all the chapters from the textbook pretty well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So finally, the question you all might be asking, how does one ace this exam? The answer is simple but a bit expensive. All the quiz questions and exam questions are recycled from the textbook so all you need to do is get your hands on the test bank, and if you can&amp;rsquo;t do that, then buy one. Even if this changes, you can&amp;rsquo;t go wrong with it as you will get a lot of practice out of it. I&amp;rsquo;d recommend buying it as a set and everyone can throw in a bit to cover the costs!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If this is unethical to you then I would recommend going through his notes and the textbook if you want to get above 80% in this course. There is a lot of reading you&amp;rsquo;d have to do so I don&amp;rsquo;t know if dedicating this much time into this course would be worth it that much.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COMM 1116 - Business Communications 1</title>
      <link>http://www.bcitcst.com/post/term1/comm1116/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2016 22:44:28 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.bcitcst.com/post/term1/comm1116/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another super simple course if you have Frank. You learn some useful things too in this, the lectures are pretty dry and you can probably learn everything he&amp;rsquo;s teaching&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COMP 1113 - Applied Mathematics</title>
      <link>http://www.bcitcst.com/post/term1/comp1113/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2016 22:44:15 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.bcitcst.com/post/term1/comp1113/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COMP 1111 - Essential Skills for Computing</title>
      <link>http://www.bcitcst.com/post/term1/comp1111/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2016 22:44:08 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.bcitcst.com/post/term1/comp1111/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is one of the more laid back and easier courses in first term where you learn about basic &amp;ldquo;how to use your computer&amp;rdquo; knowledge and get a little exposure to command line. There is no mid term or final and a majority of the marks (60%) are from the labs which are fairly straight forward and simple to do. Even though it is a simple course it does expose you to some important topic like version control and virtual machines. The rest of the marks are quizzes (20%) and a presentation you give on a topic with a group (20%). Overall a very simple course that shouldn&amp;rsquo;t give you a hard time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COMP 1100 - CST Program Fundamentals</title>
      <link>http://www.bcitcst.com/post/term1/comp1100/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2016 22:43:56 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.bcitcst.com/post/term1/comp1100/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;COMP 1100 is a pass or fail course, you just need to show up to all the lectures and do the bare minimum on the assignments and quizzes to pass the course. I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ve heard of anyone who managed to fail this course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usually, the professor brings in some speakers who come and talk about there company. I would suggest paying attention to these types of talks, maybe even write down some notes. When it comes to applying for jobs or internships, you can refer to that talk in your cover letter which will make you seem more appealing to HR.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COMP 1536 - Introduction to Web Development</title>
      <link>http://www.bcitcst.com/post/term1/comp1536/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2016 22:35:57 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.bcitcst.com/post/term1/comp1536/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This course was fairly easy but just a bit annoying at times. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.w3schools.com&#34;&gt;http://www.w3schools.com&lt;/a&gt; is probably your best friend during this course. This is a very simple course that mainly deals with HTML5 and CSS. JavaScript, AJAX, and PHP are also introduced but they aren&amp;rsquo;t the core focus of this course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was doing this with Ben, we had weekly labs and forum discussions. The labs could be done in pairs and they were very straight forward. No reading is required, when you run into a problem you just google it and figure it out. Our midterm and final consisted of multiple choices and short answers. The short answers usually required you to write small chunks of code e.g. &amp;ldquo;use inline css to give this text a colour of blue&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;write code to create a table with 2 cols and 2 rows in html&amp;rdquo;, etc. Pretty straight forward stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have Ben for this course, I&amp;rsquo;d suggest not panicking when it comes to the exams. He usually assigned us a lot of chapters before the exam but we were never actually tested on them. If you feel you haven&amp;rsquo;t been taught something thoroughly then most likely it won&amp;rsquo;t show up on the exam (at least the written part for sure).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ben usually teaches this course for the winter intakes and Medhat teaches it for the fall intakes. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how Medhat teaches this course but I&amp;rsquo;ve had Medhat for other exams and he usually keeps it simple. Pay attention to his lectures, whenever he&amp;rsquo;s doing some demonstration, take notes and you&amp;rsquo;ll be fine when it comes to quizzes and exams.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COMP 1510 - Programming Methods</title>
      <link>http://www.bcitcst.com/post/term1/comp1510/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2016 18:28:09 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.bcitcst.com/post/term1/comp1510/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Many people see this course to be extremely easy, however, I found it to be very difficult when I first started at BCIT. I failed the midterm but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean you need to. This is just a beginner&amp;rsquo;s java course however, many struggle with it and many get above 90%. It all depends on the amount of time you are willing to put into it. I&amp;rsquo;m going to tell you the things you should spend your time on and what you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;assignments-labs&#34;&gt;Assignments &amp;amp; Labs&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s quite easy to get 100% on all the labs and assignments, I remember they provide you to run tests on your program with some scripts to see if your program passes them or not. Never should you ever be handing in a program that doesn&amp;rsquo;t pass in those tests at the very least.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, these might seem difficult at first and they are somewhat but as long as you know your basics, you&amp;rsquo;ll do fine in it. Also try to get a group of friends going, if you don&amp;rsquo;t understand something, ask others. If no one understands that one thing, ask the lab instructor. And if that fails, then ask Bruce. (Bruce is the instructor of this course, he&amp;rsquo;s been teaching it for a very long time and I&amp;rsquo;m assuming he&amp;rsquo;ll continue to do this). There are also some quizzes but the quizzes test very basic things that are taught in the previous week in lectures, if you spend a little time on it you&amp;rsquo;ll for sure ace it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;midterm&#34;&gt;Midterm&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The midterm caught be by surprise because I started memorizing code to do the exam, I thought most of the exam would consist of us actually writing small chunks of code. I was very wrong&amp;hellip;haha. It was a mixture of Multiple Choice, True &amp;amp; False, and Short Answers. And it was heavily based on the first few chapters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multiple Choice and True &amp;amp; False

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;from what I hear, apparently these are taken out of the book&amp;rsquo;s test bank questions so maybe give that a shot if you are really nervous about the exam!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Short Answers

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;these consisted of very basic things such as: name all the primitive types, what kind of loops are there, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;not meant to be tricky questions but if you&amp;rsquo;re just memorizing stuff then I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how well you&amp;rsquo;ll do on this portion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;final&#34;&gt;Final&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Final was actually quite easy if you do all your labs, assignments and actually understand what&amp;rsquo;s going on rather than just making your program work. It had the same layout as our midterm but this time the short answers were asking us to write small chunks of code. This may sound like it can be really difficult but honestly, it&amp;rsquo;s not all that hard. If you get stuck on a question, at least write down something, maybe the function header, declare the variables so you can get some part marks! If you want to ace this section then I&amp;rsquo;d suggest doing some interview algorithm questions. &lt;a href=&#34;https://leetcode.com/&#34;&gt;https://leetcode.com/&lt;/a&gt; is a great place to try out these type of questions. Just do some of the easy ones and if you can figure those out then you can ace this exam no problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember this course is worth 7 credits so it weighs &lt;strong&gt;A LOT&lt;/strong&gt; on your GPA, so dedicate the most amount of hours into this! But if you still happen to do poorly in this course, it&amp;rsquo;s not the end of the road because some people (like me) just need more time than others to get a hold of the basics.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>