<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Term 2 on BCIT CST</title>
    <link>http://www.bcitcst.com/categories/term-2/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Term 2 on BCIT CST</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://www.bcitcst.com/categories/term-2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>COMP 2526 - Object-Oriented Programming with Java</title>
      <link>http://www.bcitcst.com/post/term2/comp2526/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 17:19:24 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.bcitcst.com/post/term2/comp2526/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Another fairly challening course in second term. Personally I enjoyed Dennis Richards teaching style. Its very direct and he does his best to try and get the class talking and start up a discussion. Make sure your paying attention in class as Dennis is know to pick out people who are not and grill them on a question until they get it. Seriously, PAY ATTENTION.
Lots of practice examples and ideas are written up on the overhead and I suggest you note them down and go home and write them out and play around with what is given and see what causes things to break and why. This will help you a ton for the mid term and final.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;labs&#34;&gt;Labs&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The labs are pretty much tutorials, read them carefully follow the instructions and you should be fine. There are also quizzes during the labs which just make sure you understood what happened in the last few lectures, if you did poorly on a quiz go back and figure out what you messed up because its more than likely something similar will show up on your mid term or final except harder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The midterm and final will both test your ability to both read and write code and make sure you truly understand the order of operations of a specific program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;assignments&#34;&gt;Assignments&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will be 2 or 3 assignments that are each broken down into parts. The assignments can be fairly challenging if COMP 1510 is the only Java experience you have but rest assured they are doable. Allocate enough time for the assignments and find a good study group to work and learn from and you&amp;rsquo;ll be just fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;midterm-final&#34;&gt;Midterm &amp;amp; Final&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve been compiling the code Dennis gives you in lecture and playing with on your own time to see how things break and finding the order of operations you should be able to get through the mid term and final with ease. If not, it will be tough to achieve a high mark. The whole course is about getting a deeper understanding of how Object Oriented languages works and that is what your tested on.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COMM 2216 - Business Communications 2</title>
      <link>http://www.bcitcst.com/post/term2/comm2216/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 02:35:38 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.bcitcst.com/post/term2/comm2216/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hands down the easiest course of second semester. We only did about 2 main assignments and a single presentation. Besides that there was Resume and a Cover Letter we had to do along with a job interview which was done in a group of 3 with your peers. It seemed like it might be awkward or difficult at first but it ended up being a walk in the park.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was no midterm, just a final exam. Our final exam did however contain all the things we learned which was writing a proposal and a pitch. Be prepared to go into the final exam and writing a shit load. It&amp;rsquo;s only worth 25% though so if you write down at least something that is somewhat relevant to the topic you&amp;rsquo;re provided than honestly you should be able to get 70+% in the course without even trying.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COMP 2121 - Discrete Mathematics</title>
      <link>http://www.bcitcst.com/post/term2/comp2121/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 00:15:11 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.bcitcst.com/post/term2/comp2121/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;All in all, not that bad of a course. It&amp;rsquo;s essential that you go to all the labs and lectures though, if you fail to attend them, it gets pretty difficult to pass as Goran teaches at a decently fast pace. What you learn in this course is pretty important though as you will see some of these things again in Algorithms (3rd term) and Computer Graphics (4th semester).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the weekly labs, there was always a quiz (which was brutal if you have them at 830am). The quizzes were pretty straight forward and only contained a question or two. Make sure you arrive on time for the class because Goran doesn&amp;rsquo;t wait for anyone and just gives you a 0 instead. Then there was always a lab worksheet that everyone would just slowly work through. There wasn&amp;rsquo;t much homework that you&amp;rsquo;d go home and do really so it was pretty relaxing because of that. We did get some assignments, which you can do in a pair so they weren&amp;rsquo;t something anyone would get stuck on either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The exams were a bit tricky however, probably the hardest part of this course. I personally thought the final was brutal because it was cumulative therefore it contained questions that you would like in the first few weeks(factorials, etc.) and they&amp;rsquo;d be combined with the things you learned in the last couple weeks. If you didn&amp;rsquo;t struggle much with factorials and permutations chapters then you should be able to get 80%+ easy. The hardest part is just going over all the material again.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COMP 2510 - Procedural Programming in C</title>
      <link>http://www.bcitcst.com/post/term2/comp2510/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2016 16:57:11 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.bcitcst.com/post/term2/comp2510/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;This course is probably the hardest course in second term, but it&amp;rsquo;s not as bad as some people have pictured it to be. At first, Albert comes of quite intimidating but as you get into the course, you get used to his teaching style. Textbook for this course is nonexistent so don&amp;rsquo;t go wasting your money. There&amp;rsquo;s 1 midterm, 1 final, 3 assignments and 1 lab exercise that you have to complete within your lab hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Albert moves quite fast in the lectures and it&amp;rsquo;s pretty difficult to keep up all the time. I&amp;rsquo;d recommend writing down everything word for word that he writes on the overhead while he&amp;rsquo;s presenting. Then you can go over it later and understand what he was doing and why he was doing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Friendly tip: try to always compile the small chunk of code he goes over in lectures, try making them work and understand how its working. If you can do this then honestly I don&amp;rsquo;t see you getting below 80% in this course.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re confused about something, ask someone for help, otherwise you&amp;rsquo;ll fall behind and honestly, catching up is probably the hardest thing in this course. The hardest topics are probably strings(char arrays), arrays, pointers, and memory allocation. I would really recommend watching videos on these topics before Albert introduces them to you. So when he does introduce them to you, you&amp;rsquo;re not completely lost and have somewhat of an idea about whats going on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;labs&#34;&gt;Labs&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a single lab every week that covers the topics learned in the previous week. These labs are usually free marks, if you don&amp;rsquo;t understand what the lab wants at all then work with a partner. If you&amp;rsquo;re good at math then these labs should be pretty easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;assignments&#34;&gt;Assignments&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Theres 3 assignments each worth about 10% of your overall mark I believe. Albert usually gives you tests that you can run on your assignment so you can see if your assignment meets all of the requirements or not. Pass all the tests and you&amp;rsquo;re usually guaranteed above 90% on the assignment. I&amp;rsquo;d recommend starting on the assignment as soon as it comes out, or reading it at the very least so you can process in the back of your head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;midterm-final&#34;&gt;Midterm &amp;amp; Final&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Albert always provides you with a review before the exam. The review is very very similar to the exam! Don&amp;rsquo;t try to memorize the answers as they will not be the same. Understand how you can reach the answers and work through the review sheets multiple times. Alberts exam&amp;rsquo;s aren&amp;rsquo;t meant to be tricky or hard, but, a lot of people fail the exams (especially the midterm). If you failed the midterm, it&amp;rsquo;s not the end of the road, you can still easily pass the course.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>